

#### **ABOUT**

▲ 10823 Berlin

I am a data scientist specializing in psychometrics, psycholinguistics, and modeling subjectivity. My passion is revealing and understanding heterogeneity. That translates into various unsupervised machine learning and natural language processing applications like latent profile analysis, latent class analysis, psychological profiles with psychometric networks, semantic networks, concept class analysis.

#### **SKILLS**

### **Data Science**

Proficient with

pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn

tidyverse, tidymodels, tidyflow, easystats, lavaan (and its ecosystem), psychometric networks (collection of packages), quanteda, spacy Familiar with

Tensorflow-Keras, pytorch, prophet

# **Programming**

**Proficient with** Git, Bash

### **Databases**

Familiar with

Postgres, SQLite, MongoDB

## **Deployment**

Familiar with

AWS (EC2, RDS), Docker, Flask

## EDUCATION 2021

2021	Data Science Bootcamp
	Spiced Academy, Berlin, Germany
2015 - 2018	Ph.D. in Political Science
	CvO Universität Oldenburg,
	Oldenburg, Germany
2008 - 2012	M.A. in Political Science
	Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey
2005 - 2008	M.A. in International Relations
	Galatasaray University, Istanbul,
	Turkey
1999 - 2004	B.A. in International Relations
	Istanbul Bilgi University, Istanbul,
	Turkey

## **SELECTED PROJECTS**

**Measuring Organizational Practices** 

Natural language processing

**Movie Recommender** 

Unsupervised machine learning

Image Classification with Deep Learning

Deep learning

**Dockerized Data Pipeline** 

Involves: MongoDB, ETL job (sentiment analysis), Postgres & Slackbot

## RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

02-11/2020 Postdoctoral Fellow

<u>Jacobs University</u>, Bremen, Germany

- ➤ Worked as the lead data analyst in a thirdparty funded project (<u>Business Finland</u> & <u>Hofstede</u> <u>Insights</u>) developing a dictionary that measures organizational culture with <u>Hofstede's Multi-Focus</u> <u>Model</u>
- Used the R tidy ecosystem; the quanteda ecosystem (including spacyr), rJST, tidytext, sentimentr & the easystats ecosystem

Since 02/2019

Affiliated Postdoctoral
Fellow

Bremen International School
of Social Sciences, Bremen,
Germany

Conducting research, publishing academic papers, teaching methods classes

01/2019 - 02/2020 (Interim-) Academic Coordinator

CvO Universität Oldenburg, Oldenburg, Germany

Oldenburg, Germany

07/2012 - 07/2018 Research Assistant Lecturer

CvO Universität Oldenburg, Oldenburg, Germany

## **LANGUAGES**

Turkish (Native), English (Proficient), German (Intermediate)